Today, you just get me for a solo episode.
I have taken a lot of the questions that have come in
from listeners and from people on Instagram
and I'm gonna spend some time just answering questions.
By the way, I just love the fact that you
take such an interest in what you can do
to help your kid on their education journey.
I know that there's people who listen
from all over the world who are never gonna set foot
in an alpha school because we're not in that many places.
But what I wanna do is hopefully give you
a little bit of advice and maybe some ways
that you can put some of the spirit
of what we do at alpha school
into your own homes and classrooms.
So let's go.
Are you guys ready?
Welcome to the Future of Education podcast
hosted by Mackenzie Price.
Mackenzie is the founder of a revolutionary new school model
that's disrupting education through AI.
Join us as we discuss the latest in education innovation.
All right, first question.
How can I help my brilliant and bored son
who is in third grade until an alpha school opens up here?
Well, first of all, I have so much empathy
for this question because that is exactly where I was at
when I started getting frustrated
with the education system.
My two daughters were both really bright
and they were so bored.
And so that's really when people asked me
like what made you start the school?
I was like, I just can't watch kids sit and be bored.
That said, I know that not everyone's got that option
to go find a school that is awesome.
However, a couple of things I would encourage you to do
is look around in your town just to see
if there's any other schools that are popping up
that maybe could focus a little bit more
on helping kids find that passion and interest.
There are microschools coming up all over the country.
Also tell you what I did as a mom
was I made sure to kind of pack the time
when I did have my kids at home with other things.
So for example, we ran after school science clubs
where I would invite the neighborhood kids
and friends from my daughter's class to come over
and we'd do just random experiments.
And that was anything from like
we're baking blueberry muffins
to we're doing something we saw on the internet.
Sometimes I would have an expert come in
who was maybe another parent.
I remember I had a teacher show up one time
and the goal was just to make like fun experiments.
I also think so many of the life skills
that our kids learn are from
the cool extracurricular activities that we do.
But here's the key thing that I would just encourage
any parent to focus on.
Make sure you're connecting kids with things
that they truly have a passion and interest in.
Not just the things that like,
hey, everybody in our neighborhood signs up for soccer.
So we're doing soccer.
I remember my oldest daughter,
she did one season of soccer.
It was quite clear she did not like soccer.
And you know what, I didn't make her go do more soccer
just because that's what all the kids were doing.
Find those things.
In fact, I have a friend who got into,
her daughter was really interested,
loved horses and loved archery
because she'd done some archery
during like a day camp she'd gone to.
She ended up becoming a nationally ranked
horseback archery person.
I didn't even know it was a sport,
but it's an example of something that is pretty cool
that can be done.
And so I totally feel for you.
The other thing is there are some great apps
that are out there where your kid could,
maybe go find some things they're interested
around applying math or whatever subject he's interested in.
I remember when my daughter was in second grade,
she got really interested in the Revolutionary War
because her grandma had given her a book
about the American Revolution.
I had gone to the school and said,
hey, could she work on a project in school?
The teacher said, nope, she cannot.
But I kept kind of going at it.
And eventually what we did was we worked
on a project at home and we got the teacher
to give us 10 minutes, a whopping 10 minutes of time
for her to present in front of the class,
which was a fun thing for her to do as a second grader.
So all that to say,
I really hope we'll get an alpha to wherever you are.
And in the meantime, just try to help
that really brilliant kid of yours
to just find things that he's interested in,
excited about.
Here's another thing that's actually pretty cool
that I think sometimes people forget to do.
YouTube is something that is such a fun thing
for parents and kids to watch together.
Like go watch these experiments that people do on YouTube,
watch some of the challenges that they do,
and do them together and then use those opportunities
as a time to be able to maybe ask questions.
Like, well, what would we do
if we were trying to build a squirrel catching device
like Mark Rober did?
By the way, I got to talk with him the other day.
That was pretty cool.
He's gonna do some work with our science curriculum
at Alpha, I know.
Super exciting.
He was here.
I actually wanted to get him on a podcast,
but I was busy and he was busy.
All that to say, just find things
that your kid's excited about
and find ways that you and he can connect
on going deeper into subjects,
figuring out how to become an expert on that.
Okay, this next question is from a student.
And I love when I get student questions
because I love the fact that there are kids out there
who are saying, hey, how can I take ownership
and control over my education?
And so this question actually is,
how can I become a student who is able to make decisions
for their education on their own?
Okay, I'm gonna give you a couple of examples.
So at Alpha High School,
we have high schools popping up throughout the country,
but Austin, Texas is where our main high school is.
And we've had at least four students
who have reached out to me directly on Instagram
and said, hey, I want to become a student at your school.
And those students have gotten full scholarships.
They absolutely came in and said, I'll figure this out.
Let me work on this, let me get to know.
They went through the interview process,
they did everything.
And I said, what about your parents?
Do they care?
And he's like, I'll work on my parents.
And so their parents kind of came in
towards the end of that experience.
But I love the fact that I had students
who reached out directly to me and just said,
I want to be in an environment that helps us
and how can I make that happen?
And I think that's a great thing to do.
And so the best thing you can do
is arm yourself with research.
When you're thinking about what is it
that you want to do in terms of your education,
maybe you're going to the local public high school
and you want to transfer into another district school
or you want to try one of these micro schools
or maybe you want to do online or home school,
come up with research that you can then present
to your parents around, here's why I believe
that this path is going to be best for me.
And as part of that, figure out what are your priorities?
What do you care about?
What do you feel like you want to focus on?
And I think when you present that in a way
where your parents kind of understand
this kid is really thoughtfully going about this decision
and figuring out where the right environment
is going to be for him,
I think your parents will be willing to listen to you.
Okay, here's another question I often get.
How could I implement something like your school
in my public school classrooms?
So this comes from a teacher and teachers,
you guys are awesome, you're absolute heroes.
You know, I say it all the time, you're overworked,
you're underpaid and you're underappreciated.
So I love when I hear from teachers saying,
how can I bring a little bit of the alpha spirit
into my classroom?
And I'm gonna give you a few tips of things that you can do.
So first of all, motivation, in our opinion,
is 90% of what creates a great learner.
It's being a motivated student.
And so there's a lot of different motivation mechanisms
and models that you can put into your classroom
that can help kids get excited
and they don't have to be expensive.
They can be as simple as earning stickers.
And I'm telling you, we even do a sticker motivation model
in our high school and our high school students get excited.
My daughter, who was a senior came to me
and she's like, look at this amazing super cool
Taylor Swift guitar sticker that I got
when I earned all my points for the day.
And I remember being like, you're 18
and you care and she's like,
but you've never seen this Taylor Swift sticker.
And it was, it was really cool to see.
And so you can do a lot of different things,
earning time to go do things,
earning the privilege of how you work.
Maybe you create a classroom
where you've got like a really cool space,
beanbags or something that's comfortable.
And as kids get their work done and earn their privileges,
they get to earn time to go work in that area.
That's something we absolutely incorporate a lot.
And so I think motivation is something
that unfortunately traditional schools
don't pay any attention to.
And what are the things that you can do
for individual or group motivation type of projects?
That's something that I would absolutely encourage
that you implement.
You can even do an in-school currency.
We pay our students, you can do an in-school currency.
And then maybe that money that kids earn at the end
earns them the ability to go do a volleyball game
in the park on a Saturday morning altogether.
And you figure out how to get maybe parents to chip in
to bring a pizza or something like that.
So there are ways to do it.
It does require some creativity and extra work,
which I know that you teachers already have so much of.
But there's things you can do there.
Here's a question from somebody
who has started their own micro school.
And the question is I'd love to use more AI in my micro school,
but I don't know where to start.
So there's two uses of AI that we're doing
within our schools.
The first use of AI is that we're using AI
to create individualized lesson plans
and provide assessment and direction
for students when it comes to their academics.
And we're using a lot of adaptive apps to do that.
So that might be something you're thinking
about trying to implement.
I do have good news for you.
Our time back learning platform is going to be putting out
more and more software and apps
that you will be able to use and download from the app store.
So keep an eye out for that because it's coming.
But the other way that we use AI is part of our afternoons.
We're teaching kids how to use AI tools
to do what we say is give them superpowers.
So for example, we do public speaking workshops
where our students are working on public speaking.
I was just in our four year old class yesterday.
We were having a parent meeting
talking about some of the upcoming workshops.
And we were talking about the public speaking workshop
where these four year olds in six weeks
are gonna be able to speak in front of an audience
of 40 plus people that they don't know.
And we're gonna be using some AI tools
to help them with feedback on their projection
and their eye contact and how they're speaking
and helping them memorize the speeches
that they're gonna be giving.
This is all wrapped up into like a
about the world culture kind of learning thing
that they're gonna be able to do research with their parents
about maybe where their family's from
or something like that.
And so they're using tools like that.
Here's another thing that we're doing.
We're doing a growth mindset workshop
with our four year olds as well.
And the test to pass at the end of the workshop
is that these students will be able to complete a Lego set
for 11 year old plus kids.
So these are four year olds.
And where we're using AI there is we're using AI
to record what they say to themselves
as they're going through this Lego setup process
and then be able to provide coaching
around how we can implement more growth mindset stuff.
So if they get frustrated or if they ask for help,
what are the ways that we can coach them?
That's some of the stuff we're doing
within our classrooms to help with building out life skills.
Then there's the other part of AI usage that we're teaching
is that kids can learn to do things like vibe coding
to create video games or movies and videos
or building out graphic novels,
building art through AI tools.
That is something that is gonna be such an important skill
for young people to have as they go out in the world
is not just the ability to know about
how to use AI tools now,
but how to constantly be up to date
on the newest and best technology.
In fact, I'm seeing this in my own job
is that a tool that wasn't good two weeks ago
is now suddenly so much better.
So we're always helping students kind of learn
how they can use AI tools
in really positive and healthy ways.
And that's something that you can be doing.
Now, part of that requires you to also become an expert
in all the latest and greatest AI tools.
Here's a question that I get a lot from parents
who are really worried about screen time.
And this question is,
how can I balance recommendations for screen time limits
for four and five year olds with AI learning?
Let me tell you very clearly,
there are lots of differences in types of screen time.
Not all screen time is created equal.
So letting your kid brain rot,
watching YouTube videos by themselves
or watching TikTok or as a four or five year old
just watching cartoons endlessly,
that is something very different
than giving your four year old
an ability to start working on math.
So for example, our four year olds in our pre-K classrooms
are using Mentava to do some reading lessons
that they're working on.
They're also working on math apps.
And what's amazing actually,
is in only the first half of our school year,
our four year olds have already completed their pre-K
content for both math and reading.
So these kids are coming in so far ahead of the game
and they've still got four months
before the end of the school year
when they'll then graduate to be kindergartners.
And so you can have your kid do 15 minutes a day of math
or 15 minutes of reading and phonics.
Now, one thing I do want to provide as a disclaimer,
for young children, four and five year olds especially,
there is nothing better than human reading
and connecting and reading with your kids,
making sure that they're understanding how to use phonics.
So we do a lot of that at that age group.
You cannot just solely rely on an AI app
to teach your four year old to read.
It's really important that you have that human time.
But the other thing is you can also do screen time
with your kids where they're working on creative endeavors.
Maybe they're looking at some sort of art project,
something like that.
So I think the thing that I would maybe recommend
as a parent is just when you hand your kid an iPad
or you put them in front of a computer screen,
think about what it is that they're doing.
Are they sitting passively where they're just consuming
content or are they engaging actively in what it is
that they're working on and are they learning?
That's the thing I'll think.
I do know it's a hard thing.
I remember when my kids were young,
that's right about the time that we started having
phones come out that you could watch videos on.
And it felt so easy to just say, here, take my phone.
And it made having dinner a little bit easier,
something like that at a restaurant.
I never allowed screens at dinner at home,
but I definitely fell victim to it at restaurants a lot.
And so these are things that we just,
there's a lot of balance.
But again, not all screen time is equal.
That wraps up part one of this episode,
but don't worry, there's a part two coming soon.
Thanks for listening to Mackenzie Price
and the Future of Education podcast.
If you haven't hit that subscribe button,
now is the time to do it,
so you can stay up to date on all our episodes.
You can connect with Mackenzie on social media
and be part of our daily conversation over on Instagram
at futureofunderscoreeducation.
Lastly, if you're loving what you're learning,
please leave a review wherever you listen to podcasts.
We'll be back in your feed soon,
but until then, remember, kids are limitless
and it's our job to unlock their potential.