First of all, the idea that we do not use teachers to teach academic content to students
in a teacher in front of a classroom model, and that is something that just feels so hard
for people to get their heads around because we all grew up in that system and we've always
been told like a great teacher is the key to learning something.
Welcome to the future of Education Podcast, hosted by Mackenzie Price.
Mackenzie is the founder of a revolutionary new school model that's disrupting education
through AI.
Join us as we discuss the latest in education innovation.
This next question is from a parent that is super engaged and excited.
The question is, what should I start with?
I have a one-year-old.
All right, mama or daddy of one-year-old, here's the best advice that I can give to you,
play and love and read to your kid like nobody's business.
That is the best thing.
Get your kid out, getting dirty, let him go play in the mud, go explore, go find worms,
go find tadpoles, do all that kind of cool stuff.
I promise you all these AI tools are going to be around in a few years when your kid's
getting a little bit older and you're going to be able to jump on the education train.
But the best thing that you can do with your one-year-old is just love them like crazy,
play with them like crazy, and read to them like crazy.
Ooh, I really love this next question.
What is the first and biggest mindset change that parents and children need to have in our schools?
And here's what I always tell people, as a private school, families will apply for admission,
but we don't actually base our admission on what kind of grades they had or where they scored in
their transcripts or where they already were in their assessments.
Our biggest thing that we focus on is philosophical alignment with our model of education.
And so there's probably two things.
First of all, they have to change their mind around the idea that the best way to learn
is with a teacher in front of a classroom.
And that's hard because we all grew up in that system.
So I think that's kind of the biggest thing is parents need to understand like this is different,
but it works.
Now, the other big mindset change that parents and kids need to get really comfortable with
is all around the idea of failure, that kids can be challenged, they can do hard things,
and they can fail, and they can learn so much from that failure perspective.
It actually ties in with one of our parent tenants, which is support, don't solve.
We tell parents, hey, you can support your kid, but don't go in and solve their challenges for them.
Allow them the opportunity to learn and struggle and fail.
And we even say sometimes cry on their road to success.
I'm going to combine two of these next questions that I got.
The first was, do you have an alpha homeschool program?
And the second was that they are looking for an online alpha based school for performing arts for
their kid.
And here's the good news.
Yes, we do have a homeschool program.
It's called Alpha Anywhere.
It's currently for third grade through eighth grade.
Those grades will be expanding over time, but right now we're at third grade through eighth grade.
And so regarding the performing arts part of it, one of the things that our families in Alpha Anywhere
are absolutely loving is the fact that they can spend two hours getting their academics done
and then spend the rest of the day doing all these other things.
So we have students who are interested in building out businesses.
We've got kids who are doing really hardcore athletics.
We've got kids who are doing performing arts and theater and music.
And they're able to spend their afternoons doing that.
But there's something else that's really exciting that's happening.
In Texas, we are launching a virtual program for students to be able to do our alpha school
either through Texas Sports Academy if your kid is interested in sports or our GT school program,
which is for gifted and talented kids.
And families as part of that program actually get money from the state to put towards the physical
training that their kids are doing or the GT type academic training that they want to do in the
afternoons.
The reason we're able to do that just so you know is because of the school choice
efforts that have happened in Texas.
So we'll be rolling those out to other states that have that school choice opportunity.
If you want more information on alpha anywhere, you go to alpha anywhere dot co.
Oh, this is a great question that I really love to talk about.
A lot of people will say is music like orchestra or band available at an alpha school?
And here's the answer.
Yes, we have so many awesome music opportunities, but they don't look quite like traditional school
looks like.
So for example, we've got kindergarteners who are doing a piano lab workshop where they're
learning piano instruction on a keyboard and then they're creating their own songs and they're
using AI to notate those songs and then perform them.
We did the same thing with a great panel workshop with our fourth and fifth graders too.
That was really fun to see our middle school students have been doing these awesome school of
rock things where they're not only learning how to play musical instruments, writing original
songs, learning how to play together, but then they have to market their band.
They have to create the brand for their band and their hosting events.
So they get to kind of combine some event management and some marketing management
along with what they're doing.
We actually have a student in Scottsdale.
She's 10 years old.
She released her own written song that was produced.
It is called Feet on the Ground.
It's called Feet on the Ground.
It's on Spotify and it's so totally good, you guys.
I'm serious.
Ruby is a little star.
I swear we're going to see her at the Grammys in a couple of years because she is fantastic.
And so our students get a lot of opportunity to try out musical instruments and do things,
but they're not doing traditional orchestra or band that you would see in traditional schools,
but they get a ton of musical stuff.
We've got great acting workshops that our students engage in where they're doing theater
and things like that.
We always tie in with our life skills workshops though, some other skill that they're doing.
So, you know, with an acting workshop, it's obviously public speaking is one of the things.
It may be building something out, writing their own play, writing their own music, things like that.
Oh, and you know what?
It turns out I just looked at my iPad and the next question was, do you do acting?
Yeah, we do acting.
In fact, I will tell you yesterday was the anniversary of my oldest daughter's debut
as the lead Annie in one of the plays that we did.
And it was back in 2015 and it was so cute.
Here's an interesting question.
I get a lot of people wondering about how we're going to expand our education system.
And this question is, do you think that your education system would work in any country?
The short answer is yes, I do believe it could work in any country.
The longer answer is there's got to be philosophical alignment with a couple of key
points around our model.
First of all, the idea that we do not use teachers to teach academic content to students
in a teacher in front of a classroom model.
And that is something that just feels so hard for people to get their heads around
because we all grew up in that system and we've always been told like a great teacher
is the key to learning something.
So you have to believe that now we believe a great teacher is key to our success as well.
The difference is they're focusing on motivation and emotional support,
not on conveying academic content.
So that's one of the big things.
The other big philosophy that you have to be okay with is the idea that it only takes
a couple of hours to do the academic content when you do it in our model.
And so you have to be willing to allow the rest of the day to be done differently.
And so I've had conversations with school leaders from all over the United States
and all over the world who say, wow, we'd love to take your two-hour learning program
and use that in the morning.
And then the rest of school day will still do more math, science, reading, language,
because that's just what they believe is developed.
For us, what we're doing is we're giving kids our most valuable resource,
which is time back to go do all these other cool things and develop life skills.
We're not trying to cram in more academic time.
And that's something that just from a philosophy perspective,
we have to do another kind of interesting thing around countries.
So we've done a program in Malawi with refugee students.
We've done a program in Eastern Europe with Ukrainian refugee students.
So we have had this type of model work with great success in these other countries.
And they've implemented so many of the motivation models that we use at Alpha.
Obviously, though, we do need internet, you need computers, those types of things.
I also got a few questions from you around the whole idea of college and how do we prepare kids
to be successful in college.
And we should actually do a totally separate podcast around college.
And the philosophy that Alpha has around how our kids are getting into top tier universities.
In fact, we just had two early acceptances to Stanford University, my alma mater.
Pretty exciting go card.
So that was fun to see.
But here's the question that I wanted to address was,
do extracurriculars make up for average academics when it comes to going to college?
And I think one of the things that I noticed parents have is this very ingrained belief
that in order to get into college these days, you have to have perfect grades and have taken
as many AP courses as possible and have high SATs and just really, really focus on the academic
part of it.
And here's the thing, especially in top 20 universities, all of that academic stuff
is table stakes now.
Like lots of kids have taken a bunch of APs.
Lots of kids are able to get great scores on their SATs.
And so while it's important and what you need to be able to do is show that you have the ability
to handle the academic rigor of a university by having that.
The key thing is to really stand out in some other way.
And that's often through extracurricular activities.
Now extracurricular activities aren't the same as they used to be either.
Back when I was in school and being the captain of the debate team or on the varsity tennis team,
you know, those were the things we wanted.
I think what universities are really wanting to see are the kinds of things that our students are
able to do at Alpha.
Something that's very unique, something where they've really taken an interest or a passion that
they have and they've gone and become experts and done something big with it and made an impact.
I also know, and I talked to university admissions people on a regular basis,
they want to know how you as a student are going to impact the school's community.
And so those are the things to think of.
Last piece of advice that I'm going to give to parents listening to this,
especially at the high school level.
You cannot force your kids to do what you think is what they should be doing.
Find the thing that they're excited about, that they're passionate about,
and encourage them to go big.
Now you can still have a high standard of excellence for it,
and you can give them support for this, but you cannot make your kid go do things.
I am on a college admissions Facebook page,
and I'm amazed at how many parents are literally trying to live their children's life for them
very blatantly against their children's even wishes.
And please stop doing that if you're one of those parents.
Don't do that.
Instead, help your kid find the thing that they love and help them develop
the desire to be self-driven because they're excited about their passion.
Again, you can still have high standards for them,
but help them go find the thing they love.
So if you're a control freak, which I am too, by the way,
channel that energy instead of saying like, you must do this,
channel that energy into helping them find the thing that they're excited about and love.
And it may take a few tries.
It may take things.
My daughter's a great example.
My youngest daughter, she used social media as her main extracurricular.
What person in the world would think, oh, I know.
I think my daughter should just spend all her time on TikTok.
Well, 2.3 million followers later and a lot of success.
It turned out that she was able to channel this interest she had in this past time
into something really, really helpful and really valuable.
Okay, thank you so much for so many of the questions that you got.
This was really fun.
I loved watching these come in on my stories when I posted this on Instagram.
And feel free to keep them coming too.
We love getting to read the messages that you send.
And we'll do another one of these if you guys liked it.
So have a great one.
Thanks for listening to Mackenzie Price and the Future of Education podcast.
If you haven't hit that subscribe button, now is the time to do it.
So you can stay up to date on all our episodes.
You can connect with Mackenzie on social media
and be part of our daily conversation over on Instagram
at futureofunderscoreeducation.
Lastly, if you're loving what you're learning,
please leave a review wherever you listen to podcasts.
We'll be back in your feed soon.
But until then, remember, kids are limitless.
And it's our job to unlock their potential.